It is terrific that you're hanging on in there and making such great progress with this course.
포기하지 않고 코스를 잘 통과해서 정말 대단해요
As we enter the final few days of building really important expertise on the topic for today, for week
이제 마지막 며칠이 남았네요 오늘 8주 차를 위한 중요한 전문 지식을 쌓아야 해요
eight.
셋째 날은 계속해서 실력을 강화하고 한 단계 발전시키면서 기존 기술을
revise some of the stuff that we've done in the past.
수정하는 날이에요
So today we're going to look at something new.
오늘은 새로운 걸 살펴볼 거예요
Structured outputs, which is something actually that is quite a recent innovation, a way that you
구조적인 출생 작품이란 최근에 나온 혁신으로 개척 모델에
can tell frontier models that you want them to respond according to a particular specification.
특정 기준에 따라 반응하라고 말할 수 있는 방법이죠
So we'll be doing that today.
오늘 할 거예요
And we're also just going to be doing more work experience with frontier models, carrying out something
또한 프론티어 모델과 함께 작업 경험을 더 쌓을 거예요 첫 주의 콜백 같은
which is going to be a throwback, a callback to the first week, because we're going to be doing some
걸 작업하는 거죠 과거에 작업했던 것처럼 인터넷 스크랩페이지를
internet scrappage, as we had done in the past, and using frontier models to help synthesize data.
만들 건데 프론티어 모델을 이용해 데이터를 합성할 거예요
You remember we wrote a summarizer A way back.
예전에 요약본 쓴 거 기억하시죠?
The Reader's Digest of the internet was our week.
인터넷 독자 다이제스트는 우리의 한 주였어요
One day, one instant gratification.
어느 날 갑자기 만족감이 밀려왔죠
Well, we're taking that a couple of notches further.
우린 그걸 몇 단계 더 발전시킬 거예요
Um, so that's the plan for today.
그게 오늘 계획이에요
And a lot of this, again, is going to be about revising and building and experimenting.
이것 역시 많은 부분을 수정하고 만들고 실험하는 과정이죠
So let me just say a few words about structured outputs.
구조화된 출력물에 대해 몇 마디만 할게요
So structured outputs.
구조화된 출력물이죠
You remember in the past we've used JSON generation.
과거에 JSON 세대 사용했던 거 기억하시죠?
We've we've said that we want the model to respond with an output format in JSON.
JSON 내의 출력 형식으로 모델이 반응하길 원한다고 했죠
And then in the prompt we describe exactly what that JSON should look like.
프롬프트에서 JSON이 정확히 어떻게 보여야 하는지 설명하죠
And it's not 100% reliable.
100% 믿을 수도 없고요
It's actually very good.
아주 맛있어요
It's it's uh, frequently, uh, if not almost all the time will respond with JSON.
그건 자주, 거의 항상 JSON으로 응답해요
But where it starts to, to go wonky is if you've got really complicated objects that you need it to
하지만 삐뚤어지기 시작하는 건 아주 복잡한 개체가 있어서 응답해야
respond in, um, it will after a while, potentially hallucinate in some parts or give back wrong formats.
할 경우예요 시간이 지나면 일부 부분이 환각으로 나타나거나 잘못된 포맷을 보낼 수 있죠
So the idea of structured outputs was to be more directive about specifying exactly how the model should
구조적인 출력이라는 건 모델이 어떻게 반응해야 하는지 정확히 지시하는
respond.
거예요
And the way you do that is you define the response with a class, with a Python class, and it's actually
그렇게 하는 방법은 클래스로 응답을 정의하는 겁니다 Python 클래스로요 사실 그건 클래스가 될 겁니다 파이디언틱의
going to be a class which is going to be a subclass of something called base model from Pydantic, which
베이스 모델이란 것의 서브클래스가 될 거예요 엔지니어링을 전공하신다면
you may have already had experience with if you're from an engineering background, but don't worry.
이미 경험해 보셨을 수도 있지만 걱정 마세요
If not, I will show you.
아니면 보여 줄게요
Uh, you make a subclass of base model, and you use that to describe exactly what you're looking for.
기본 모델의 서브클래스를 만들어서 여러분이 찾는 걸 정확히 설명하는 데 사용하죠
Um, and then you specify that class when you call OpenAI, and it will create an instance of that class
그런 다음 OpenAI를 호출할 때 해당 클래스를 지정합니다 그럼 해당 클래스의 인스턴스를 생성해 여러분에게
in what it sends back to you.
다시 보내죠
Um, and so that's the, the idea, it's useful, as I say, for generating data in precisely a structure
필요한 구조로 데이터를 생성하는 데 유용한 개념이죠
It needs to be compared with an alternative approach, which is use of tools function calling that we
다른 접근법과 비교해봐야 합니다 도구 함수 호출 사용이죠 좀 전에
looked at again some time ago.
다시 살펴봤어요
Um, and they, they, they both they're quite similar techniques for ensuring that a particular, um,
둘 다 꽤 비슷한 기술이에요 모델로부터 특정한
uh, type of, of structure comes back in the response from the model.
구조의 반응을 확실히 가져오죠
And there's pros and cons of both of them.
둘 다 장단점이 있어요
Generally speaking, the recommendation is that if you are going to be hooking up your model directly
일반적으로 권장하는 건 모델을 응용 프로그램 코드에 직접 연결할
to application code so that it's going to be making calls to functions which need to have a particular
경우 특정 메서드 서명이 필요한 함수를 호출할 때 함수 호출과
method signature, then it's better to use function calling and tools.
도구를 사용하는 게 낫다는 거죠
That is the the better model, because then it will absolutely respond according to that JSON structure
그게 더 나은 모델이죠 그럼 완전히 반응할 테니까요 여러분이 정의한 JSON 구조에
that you've defined with the right parameters for calling your function.
따라서요 여러분의 함수를 호출하기 위한 올바른 매개 변수로요
If what you're looking at is to try and generate data in a particular format for downstream consumption
만약 여러분이 보고자 하는 것이 다운스트림 소비를 위한 특정 포맷의 데이터를 생성하는
or something, uh, then structured outputs is the way.
것이라면 구조화된 출력화가 방법이에요
Uh, so those are some of the pros and cons, and it's something that you get a feel for after you've
장단점이 이렇게 나뉘어 있는데요. 한동안 시도하고 나면 어느
tried it for a while and get to appreciate when one performs better than the other.
쪽이 더 잘했는지 알게 되고, 어느 쪽이 더 잘했는지도 알게 되죠.
But with that introduction, let's head over to JupyterLab.
소개를 마쳤으니 유피터랩으로 가보죠. HDMI
We're going to try it out for ourselves.
직접 시험해 보려고요